Seymour Specialty Wire Company Records 1993.0039
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Seymour Specialty Wire Company Records
1895-1992
1993.0039
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
52.5 Linear feet
The collection contains administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, maps, notes, publications, preliminary sketches, blueprints, and microfilm from the Seymour Manufacturing Company and the Seymour Specialty Wire Company. The Seymour Manufacturing Company, later renamed the Seymour Specialty Wire Company, produced brass products at several mills along the Naugatuck River for over one hundred years, before closing in 1991.
Seymour Specialty Wire Company.
History
The Seymour Specialty Wire Company was founded as the Seymour Manufacturing Company in 1878 by the Matthies family. The company produced brass products, at several mills along the Naugatuck River, for over one hundred years before closing in 1991. In 1984 workers at the company purchased the declining business from its owners, and it became the biggest employee owned industrial firm in the United States. Due to declining production however, the company closed in 1991.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, maps, notes, publications, preliminary sketches, blueprints, and microfilm from the Seymour Manufacturing Company and the Seymour Specialty Wire Company. The collection contains materials from the company's founding until the records were donated in 1993. Among the many subjects discussed in the collection there are materials related to company equipment and the mills, job descriptions, production, personnel, taxes, use and occupancy insurance, LIFO, trademarks, stock transfers, the United States Department of Labor, profit and loss analysis, insurance claims (accidents), labor and compensations, social security, lawsuits, pensions, and the United States War Department.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Provenance and Acquisition
The records were donated by Thomas Industries of New Haven, Connecticut, in 1993.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of Connecticut business records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Administrative Records.; Correspondence.; Financial Records.; Legal Records.; Manuals.; Microfilm.; News clippings.
- Series I: Inventory, 1895-1992
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, map, notes, publications, 1954-1955, 1959, 1961-1965, 1967-1969, 1971, 1974, 1978, 1980-1981, 1984-1986, 1988-1992 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents Note
    [Subjects include: Personnel and labor.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, maps/preliminary sketches, notes, photographs, publications, 1950s - 1980s (Box 2)
    [Subjects include: Equipment and Physical plant.]
  - Administrative records, manuals, notes, 1950s - 1991 (Box 3)
    [Subjects include: Computer system, job descriptions.]
  - Administrative records, financial records, notes, 1950s-1980s (Box 4)
    Scope and Content Note
    [Subjects include: Equipment.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, legal documents, notes, 1952, 1958, 1959, 1960s, 1970s, 1983, 1985, 1986 (Box 5)
    [Subjects include: Equipment, labor.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, legal documents, notes, preliminary sketches/maps, publications, 1948, 1949, 1950s, 1960s, 1970s, 1980-81, 1987 (Box 6)
    [Subjects include: Labor, production.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, notes, 1930s - 1980s (Box 7)
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, notes, 1949s - 1980s (Box 8)
  - Administrative records, financial records, legal documents, notes, publications, 1945 - 1980s (Box 9)
    [Subjects include: Equipment, labor, production.]
  - Administrative records, legal documents, notes, publication, flier, 1945, 1948, 1950s, 1960s, 1970s, 1980-1981, 1985 (Box 10)
    [Subjects include: Personnel, job descriptions.]
  - Correspondence, financial records, legal documents, notes, 1930s, 1940s, 1950s, 1960s (Box 11)
    [Subjects include: Taxes, use & occupancy insurance, "LIFO", trademarks, stock transfers, US Dept. of Labor.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, notes, preliminary sketch/print, 1940s, 1950s, 1960s (Box 12)
    [Subjects include: Phosphor Bronze Company (equipment, trade reports, taxes, negotiation).]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal records, 1929-1946, 1940s, 1950s, 1960s, 1976 (Box 13)
    [Subjects include: Authorizations, Benedict Mfg. Company, insurance, personnel payroll, profit and loss analysis.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, notes, 1916-1930s, 1940s (Box 14)
    [Subjects include: Connecticut Hospital Service Inc., Credit Men, Diamond Silver Company, Guanajuato Reduction & Mines Company, International Lock and Products Company (bankruptcy, American Brass Company), Seymour Water Company, social security, taxes, Town of West Haven loss analysis.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, preliminary sketches (blueprints), 1930s, 1940s, 1950s, 1960s (Box 15)
    [Subjects include: Department of Commerce, Engineering Department, finances.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, notes, publications, 1930s, 1940s, 1950s, 1960s (Box 16)
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, notes, 1947-1950s, 1960-1961 (Box 17)
    [Subjects include: Accounting, dissolution, renegotiation, repairs, resolutions, Rufert Chemical Company, scrap handling, Secretary of State, social security, tax.]
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, notes, preliminary sketches/maps, publications, 1918-1920s, 1930s, 1940s, 1950s, 1960-1962 (Box 18)
    [Subjects include: New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, nickel investigation, Pershing Ave. and Shelton St. property, pricing, Providence office, public liability insurance, social security, State of New York, tax, wire mill plans and specifications.]
  - Administrative records, book (1), correspondence, legal documents, notes, preliminary sketches/maps/blueprints, 1940s, 1950s, 1960 (Box 19)
    [Subjects include: Accounting, casting shop, Comstock & Wescott Inc., H.A. Matthews Manufacturing Company, management, materials/products, New Jersey Zinc Company, payroll, pension, pricing, production, Rolling Mill, social security, tax, West Haven property, Wire Mill.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, notes, 1920s, 1930s, 1940s, 1950s (Box 20)
    [Subjects include: Costs, metals, production/orders, profit and loss analysis.]
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, financial records, notes, photographs, preliminary sketches/maps/blueprints, publications, 1917-1945, 1940s, 1950s, 1960-1961 (Box 21)
    [Subjects include: H.A. Matthews Manufacturing Company, State Highway Department/Engineering Department, patents, prices/materials/products, stock, tax, WWII.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, legal documents, notes, publications, 1939, 1940s, 1950-1952 (Box 22)
    [Subjects include: World War II production.]
  - Administrative records, clippings (1), correspondence, flier (1), legal records, notes, photographs, preliminary sketches/drawings, publications, 1940s, 1950-1954 (Box 23)
    [Subjects include: World War II.]
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, legal documents, notes, preliminary sketch/drawing (1), publications, 1940s, 1950-1953 (Box 24)
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, notes, photographs, publications, sketches, 1950s, 1968, 1971, 1980s, 1990-1992 (Box 25)
    [Subjects include: company files.]
  - Administrative records, financial records, 1895-1952, 1957-1958 (Box 26)
    [Subjects include: Metals, other equipment/supplies/materials/products.]
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, fliers, legal documents, notes, publications, 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, fliers, legal documents, notes, publications, sketch/map, 1984-1987 (Box 28)
  - Administrative records, blueprints, correspondence, financial records, fliers, notes, preliminary/preparatory drawings/sketches, publications, 1950s, 1960s, 1970s, 1980s (Box 29)
    [Subjects include: Chadwick's office.]
  - Administrative records, blueprints, clippings, correspondence, financial records, fliers, notes, photographs, postcards, preliminary/preparatory drawings/sketches, publications, 1941, 1946, 1956, 1957, 1959, 1960s, 1970s, 1980s (Box 30)
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, legal documents, publications, 1948-1949, 1950s, 1970, 1975, 1980s (Box 31)
    [Subjects include: Mill products, meetings, directors, stockholders, finances.]
  - Microforms (microfilm), 1916-50, 1952, 1955-1956 (Box 32)
    [Subjects include: Seymour Manufacturing Company, payroll.]
  - Financial records, notes, 1947-1949, 1954-1955 (Box 33)
    [Subjects include: Phosphor Bronze payroll.]
  - Financial records, 1935, 1942, 1946-1947, 1949-1955 (Box 34)
  - Financial records, postcard (1), notes, 1933, 1939-1941, 1944, 1947-1951 (Box 35)
  - Financial records, notes, 1930-1932, 1934-1937, 1940-1941, 1943, 1945-1946, 1948-1950 (Box 36)
  - Financial records, notes, 1945, 1948-1956 (Box 37)